<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Shivam</title><subtitle>A minimal, portfolio, sidebar, bootstrap Jekyll theme with responsive web design and focuses on text presentation.</subtitle> <updated>2021-07-30T11:58:35+05:30</updated> <author> <name>Shivam Kumar</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Shivam Kumar </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Django Rest API similar to Pastebin</title><link href="/posts/rest-api/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Django Rest API similar to Pastebin" /><published>2021-05-20T11:20:20+05:30</published> <updated>2021-07-30T11:57:48+05:30</updated> <id>/posts/rest-api/</id> <content src="/posts/rest-api/" /> <author> <name>Shivam Kumar</name> </author> <category term="ALL_PROJECTS" /> <summary> Introduction Created a Model backed Browsable API which let user’s share their code or any other text by creating snippets using the API. Additionally users have all the CRUD functionality with object level permission management and can change a few aesthetics. Features and Components MVT design pattern In actual it resembles MVC the only diffrence is that Controller in MVC... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Django Stocks App</title><link href="/posts/stocks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Django Stocks App" /><published>2021-05-10T11:20:20+05:30</published> <updated>2021-05-10T11:20:20+05:30</updated> <id>/posts/stocks/</id> <content src="/posts/stocks/" /> <author> <name>Shivam Kumar</name> </author> <category term="ALL_PROJECTS" /> <summary> Stocks App Introduction A web site where you can view quotes of various companies just by entering their ticker symbol. You can search for multiple quotes by entering multiple ticker symbols in comma separated form in the search box. Additionaly you can keep track of your favorite companies quotes by adding them to your portfolio. All the datas are fetched from API and displayed after form... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Node.js Authentication System</title><link href="/posts/node-auth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Node.js Authentication System" /><published>2021-04-15T11:20:20+05:30</published> <updated>2021-07-29T00:43:23+05:30</updated> <id>/posts/node-auth/</id> <content src="/posts/node-auth/" /> <author> <name>Shivam Kumar</name> </author> <category term="ALL_PROJECTS" /> <summary> Introduction Node.js authentication system with functionality of login, logout, register, email verification, change password , reset password, delete account etc. It uses passport authentication, express session maintainance, bcrypt for password hashing, nodemailer and OAuth2 to generate and send emails , JWT token to generate verification and reset links and mongodb as database to store ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Real Estate Web Application</title><link href="/posts/real-estate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real Estate Web Application" /><published>2020-04-10T11:20:20+05:30</published> <updated>2021-07-18T00:07:12+05:30</updated> <id>/posts/real-estate/</id> <content src="/posts/real-estate/" /> <author> <name>Shivam Kumar</name> </author> <category term="ALL_PROJECTS" /> <summary> Introduction A sample Real Estate web app for sales, purchase and search of suitable housing properties available for rent or sale. It includes login pages for manager and agents and home page for customers to search and find suitable property and then contact the respective agents, session management using JSP and data fetching from MySQL database. Features and functionalities Search f... </summary> </entry> </feed>
